<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Codurance</title>
    <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href=""/>
    <updated>2015-04-15T13:32:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://codurance.com</id>
    <author>
        <name>Codurance</name>
        <email>hello@codurance.com</email>
    </author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) Codurance</rights>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2015/04/15/design-patterns-in-the-21st-century-part-three/</id>
        <title>Design Patterns in the 21st Century: The Adapter Pattern</title>
        <link href="/2015/04/15/design-patterns-in-the-21st-century-part-three/"/>
        <published>2015-04-15T13:00:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is part three of my talk, &lt;a href=&quot;http://talks.samirtalwar.com/design-patterns-in-the-21st-century.html&quot;&gt;Design Patterns in the 21st Century&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2015/04/15/making-sense-of-docker-volumes/</id>
        <title>Making Sense of Docker Volumes</title>
        <link href="/2015/04/15/making-sense-of-docker-volumes/"/>
        <published>2015-04-15T09:00:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.docker.com&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; is a platform that allows users to build, ship, and run distributed applications. Applications are stored inside &lt;strong&gt;docker containers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2015/04/14/design-patterns-in-the-21st-century-part-two/</id>
        <title>Design Patterns in the 21st Century: The Abstract Factory Pattern</title>
        <link href="/2015/04/14/design-patterns-in-the-21st-century-part-two/"/>
        <published>2015-04-14T09:00:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is part two of my talk, &lt;a href=&quot;http://talks.samirtalwar.com/design-patterns-in-the-21st-century.html&quot;&gt;Design Patterns in the 21st Century&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2015/04/13/design-patterns-in-the-21st-century-part-one/</id>
        <title>Design Patterns in the 21st Century, Part One</title>
        <link href="/2015/04/13/design-patterns-in-the-21st-century-part-one/"/>
        <published>2015-04-13T11:30:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been having a bit of trouble blogging recently. In an effort to get back into it, I thought I&#39;d take &lt;a href=&quot;http://talks.samirtalwar.com/design-patterns-in-the-21st-century.html&quot;&gt;a talk that I presented at JAX London last year&lt;/a&gt;, split it up into blog-sized posts as it&#39;s pretty long, and post them all week. If you haven&#39;t read it before or seen the talk, I hope you enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2015/03/29/dangerous-words/</id>
        <title>Dangerous Words</title>
        <link href="/2015/03/29/dangerous-words/"/>
        <published>2015-03-29T21:22:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ludwig Wittgenstein was one the greatest philosophers of 20th century. His book Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus addresses the limits of language and its relationship with reality. A friend of mine, great polemicist, suggested me to read it some years ago to understand one of his favourites conversational &lt;em&gt;deux ex machina&lt;/em&gt;: &quot;I can&#39;t prove that, because of the inherent insufficiency of the language.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2015/03/23/multiple-projects-in-visual-studio/</id>
        <title>Multiple projects in Visual Studio solutions considered harmful</title>
        <link href="/2015/03/23/multiple-projects-in-visual-studio/"/>
        <published>2015-03-23T22:49:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Multiple projects in Visual Studio solutions considered harmful&lt;/h1&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2015/03/23/project-sizing/</id>
        <title>Project Sizing</title>
        <link href="/2015/03/23/project-sizing/"/>
        <published>2015-03-23T14:30:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sizing a project is one of the most important things we do and it is often the first thing we need precisely when we have the least amount of information. During a pre-sales meeting the client will usually ask for a &quot;ballpark&quot; figure so that they can understand if the project is feasible. We try to get as much information as possible before we provide a very high-level figure. The approach we take depends on whether the client already has a well defined backlog or if they are expecting us to create the backlog as part of the estimation.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2015/03/20/user-stories-guidelines/</id>
        <title>User Story Guidelines</title>
        <link href="/2015/03/20/user-stories-guidelines/"/>
        <published>2015-03-20T21:22:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: This post was extracted from an internal Codurance document used to help our apprentices to learn how we work. We all understand that each project is different and that by no means we can apply exactly the same techniques and practices everywhere. However, the text below serves not only as a foundation but also as a guideline for all of us when it comes to user stories. There are many good books and posts written about user stories. By no means this post is meant to be a summary of all the good practices around this area.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2015/03/17/javascript_a_tough_love/</id>
        <title>JavaScript - A Tough Love</title>
        <link href="/2015/03/17/javascript_a_tough_love/"/>
        <published>2015-03-17T10:49:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the 90’s we were witnesses of browser wars. Wars which created one of the most hated languages: Javascript. Web designers touch by Javascript at the beginning of 21st century constantly refused to fix bugs titled as “It doesn’t work in Internet Explorer” or “Netscape Navigator doesn’t show…”. At this time we used pure languages and tried to understand the design of our web browser in order to cope with compatibility issues.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2015/03/16/installing-zprezto-a-quick-guide/</id>
        <title>How to install Prezto with Zsh for your OS X Terminal</title>
        <link href="/2015/03/16/installing-zprezto-a-quick-guide/"/>
        <published>2015-03-16T22:49:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Once in a while, whether it be by someone I&#39;m pairing with or someone who&#39;s just peeked over my shoulder, I&#39;ll get asked how I &quot;got my terminal to look like that&quot;. From now on I&#39;m just going to direct them to this post as I&#39;m going to take a short while to explain how I achieved the colourful canvas I log into every day.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2015/03/15/rethinking-pair-programming/</id>
        <title>Rethinking Pair Programming</title>
        <link href="/2015/03/15/rethinking-pair-programming/"/>
        <published>2015-03-15T22:49:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;By default, we always do our work in pairs. We strongly believe that the quality achieved by two people working on the same task is superior to when done by a single person. However, there are times where pairing is not very efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2015/01/27/balanced-abstraction-principle/</id>
        <title>Balanced Abstraction Principle</title>
        <link href="/2015/01/27/balanced-abstraction-principle/"/>
        <published>2015-01-27T10:30:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the things that make code complicated to read and understand is when the instructions inside a method are at different levels of abstraction.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2015/01/09/impact-mapping/</id>
        <title>Impact Mapping</title>
        <link href="/2015/01/09/impact-mapping/"/>
        <published>2015-01-09T10:30:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We had the pleasure to visit a client who asked us to facilitate a workshop. The aim was to create a plan for their investors in order to release the next round of funding for a social media website. They had a product backlog that was full of of features but they were not sure how to prioritise them. They also had a release roadmap but were unclear as to why certain things needed to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2014/12/13/naming-test-classes-and-methods/</id>
        <title>Naming Test Classes and Methods</title>
        <link href="/2014/12/13/naming-test-classes-and-methods/"/>
        <published>2014-12-13T00:27:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What should my first test be? What should I test next? These are common questions that I&#39;m asked over and over again. I quite often ask these questions myself. Deciding on what to test is hard. Deciding on the order that things should be tested is even harder.[^1] But writing tests first is not the only problem. How often did we get frustrated while dealing with existing tests which we had no idea what they are testing?&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>/2014/12/06/life-as-an-apprentice/</id>
        <title>What is it like to be a Codurance Apprentice?</title>
        <link href="/2014/12/06/life-as-an-apprentice/"/>
        <published>2014-12-06T18:31:00+00:00</published>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This month Codurance is celebrating its first birthday. A lot has happened during that time, including the hiring of two apprentices. One of which, I am pleased to say is me!&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
        
    </entry>
    
</feed>